Danyang Zhuo

Assistant Professor Department of Computer Science Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Duke University December 12, 2020
308 Research Dr
Durham, NC 27705
danyang@cs.duke.edu
https://danyangzhuo.com

Research Interests

I do research broadly in computer systems, including operating systems, distributed systems, and computer networks, with a focus on the design and implementation of data center systems to support today's increasingly data-intensive applications (e.g., deep learning, big data analytics, packet processing). My approaches include software architecture design, programming languages, and machine learning.

Education

University of Washington - Seattle

Seattle, Washington

Ph.D. in Computer Science and Engineering

Sep 2013 - Aug 2019

- Dissertation: Practical, Efficient, and Reliable Data Center Communication.
- Advisors: Thomas E. Anderson, Arvind Krishnamurthy

University of Illinois - Urbana Champaign

B.S. in Electrical Engineering

Urbana, Illinois Aug 2009 - May 2013

Advisor: Nitin Vaidya

Professional Experience

Duke University
Assistant Professor of Computer Science

University of California – Berkeley

 $Postdoctoral\ Researcher$

- Advisor: Ion Stoica

Microsoft Research

Contractor (through Populous Group)

Microsoft Research

Research Intern

Google

Software Development Engineering Intern

Amazon

Software Development Engineering Intern

Microsoft

• Software Development Engineering Intern

Durham, North Carolina

Jul 2020 - now

Berkeley, California Sep 2019 - Jun 2020

Redmond, Washington Oct 2015 - Feb 2017

Redmond, Washington

Jun 2015 - Sep 2015

Mountain View, California

Sep 2014 - Mar 2015

Seattle, Washington

May 2013 - Sep 2013

Redmond, Washington

May 2012 - Aug 2012

Publications

Conference Papers

- 1. Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Mengqi Chen, Ryan Jennings, Ang Chen, **Danyang Zhuo**, Thomas Anderson. *High Velocity Kernel File Systems with Bento*. The 19th USENIX Conference on File and Storage Technologies (FAST), 2021.
- Lianmin Zheng, Chengfan Jia, Minmin Sun, Zhao Wu, Cody Hao Yu, Ameer Haj-Ali, Yida Wang, Jun Yang, **Danyang Zhuo**, Koushik Sen, Joseph E. Gonzalez, Ion Stoica. *Ansor: Generating High-Performance Tensor Programs for Deep Learning*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Operating Systems Design and Implementation (OSDI), 2020.
- 3. Kaiyuan Zhang, **Danyang Zhuo**, Arvind Krishnamurthy. *Gallium: Automated Software Middlebox Offloading to Programmable Switches*. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2020.
- 4. Kaiyuan Zhang, **Danyang Zhuo**, Aditya Akella, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Xi Wang. *Automated Verification of Customizable Middlebox Properties with Gravel*. The 17th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2020.
- Danyang Zhuo, Kaiyuan Zhang, Yibo Zhu, Hongqiang Harry Liu, Matthew Rockett, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network. The 16th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2019.
- Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Klaus-Tycho Förster, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center* Networks. In Proceedings of the Conference of the ACM Special Interest Group on Data Communication (SIGCOMM), 2017.
- 7. Danyang Zhuo, Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, Xuan Kelvin Zou, Hang Guan, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. *RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks*. The 14th USENIX Symposium on Networked Systems Design and Implementation (NSDI), 2017.
- 8. Vincent Liu, **Danyang Zhuo**, Simon Peter, Arvind Krishnamurthy and Thomas E. Anderson. Subways: A Case for Redundant, Inexpensive Data Center Edge Links. The 13th International Conference on emerging Networking EXperiments and Technologies (CoNEXT), 2015.

Workshop Papers

- Samantha Miller, Kaiyuan Zhang, Danyang Zhuo, Shibin Xu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas Anderson. Practical Safe Linux Kernel Extensibility. The 17th Workshop on Hot Topics in Operating Systems (HotOS), 2019.
- Danyang Zhuo, Qiao Zhang, Xin Yang, Vincent Liu. Canaries in the Network. The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.
- 3. **Danyang Zhuo**, Qiao Zhang, Vincent Liu, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Rack-level Congestion Control.* The 15th ACM Workshop on Hot Topics in Networks (HotNets), 2016.

4. **Danyang Zhuo**, Qiao Zhang, Dan Ports, Arvind Krishnamurthy, Thomas E. Anderson. *Machine Fault Tolerance for Reliable Datacenter Systems*. The 5th Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys), 2014.

Patents

1. Monia Ghobadi, Ratul Mahajan, Amar Phanishayee, **Danyang Zhuo**, Xuan Kelvin Zou. *Data Center Topology Having Multiple Classes of Reliability*. US Patent 20170302565A1. WIPO Patent 2017180450A1.

Students

Current PhD Students

Jingrong Chen (2020-), Guozhen She (2020-), Xinhao Kong (2021-)

Awards

University of Washington Madrona Prize Runner-Up	2018
University of Washington Hacherl Endowed Fellowship	2014
Rank 146th in the William Lowell Putnam Mathematical Competition	2012

Invited Talk

•	Towards Efficient and Reliable Data Center Systems.	

- Yale University	Apr 2019
- Purdue University	Apr 2019
- University of Virginia	Mar 2019
- Duke University	Mar 2019
- Rutgers University	Mar 2019
- Microsoft Research	Mar 2019
- Penn State University	Feb 2019
- University of Minnesota	Feb 2019
• Slim: OS Kernel Support for a Low-Overhead Container Overlay Network.	
- Princeton University	$\mathrm{Jun}\ 2020$
- USENIX NSDI	Feb 2019
• Understanding and Mitigating Packet Corruption in Data Center Networks.	

• RAIL: A Case for Redundant Arrays of Inexpensive Links in Data Center Networks.

Teaching

• CPS 510: Advanced Operating Systems. (Fall 2020)

Service

Program Committee

• SIGCOMM (2020)